Software Engineer sethdan

## Summary

Full-stack Python engineer creating software for 17+ years. I have a passion for solving difficult problems with cutting-edge technology and delivering products that people love. Currently in the financial/legal industry focused on system architecture, back-end web services, data pipelines, and machine learning.

### **Skills**

Languages Python, SQL, JavaScript, Go, PHP, Q/kdb+, Bash, RegEx, C#

Python Flask, scikit-learn, pytest, Pandas, SQLAlchemy ORM, Django, Selenium

Web HTML, CSS, NGINX, JQuery, Bootstrap, Wordpress, React, Apache, SSL, REST

Databases PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite, SOLR, Redis, StatsD

Operating Systems Linux (Ubuntu), MacOS, Windows
Paradigms Test-driven development (TDD), Agile

Tools Vim, Git, Docker, SSH, JIRA, Slack, Sketch, AWS, Google Analytics

# Work Experience

### Intelligize

LexisNexis

Early hire at Intelligize, a SaaS platform for legal and financial research. During my 4+ years at Intelligize:

- Active users grew more than 400%
- Total users grew more than 300%
- Intelligize was acquired by LexisNexis with technology I developed as a key selling point

#### **Technical Product Manager**

New York, NY *January 2019–Present* 

• Oversaw rearchitecture of the back-end services that power Intelligize's most critical applications

- Helped CTO manage 60+ developers
- Conceptualized and designed user interface mock-ups
- Interviewed customers, sales and support teams to ideate and prioritize projects
- Designed system components and delivered requirements to engineering teams
- Oversaw the redesign of front-end components to use React

Skills used: Product management, database design, JIRA, Sketch, Agile

#### Software Engineer

New York, NY

September 2016-January 2019

LexisNexis

- Designed and built financial research software for the web
- Built a machine learning algorithm to classify financial risk factors
- Built an application for tracking and classifying correspondences between public companies and the SEC
- Built a system to match stock ticker codes with companies' public filings
- Built a QC panel for normalizing law firm entity names
- Built dashboards to monitor application speed, reliability and data integrity

New York, NY 714-351-2115 sethdan@gmail.com

- Built software for continuously maintaining and improving these systems
- Oversaw legacy code migration and improvement of code quality

Skills used: Python, scikit-learn, Pandas, Flask, Selenium, RegEx, C#, HTML, CSS, MySQL, SOLR, Ubuntu, AWS, web scraping, API development

Data Analyst

New York, NY

November 2014-September 2016

Intelligize

- Retrieved and analyzed financial data
- Wrote scripts and defined procedures for importing newly acquired data sets
- Built working proof-of-concept demos
- Documented system behavior and flow
- Developed complex SQL reports for business intelligence and sales teams
- Developed and oversaw implementation of machine learning technology, including algorithms for classification, clustering, and document similarity analysis

Skills used: Python, SQL, MySQL, statistics, data science, scikit-learn, Pandas, RegEx, HTML, CSS, iPython/Jupyter Notebook, Selenium, Excel, Google Analytics, C#

#### Community & Alliance Manager

Toronto, ON (remote) July 2014–November 2014

ScribbleLive

- Integrated a real-time social content delivery platform into customers' websites
- Identified bugs and worked with developers to improve system architecture
- Collected client feedback and determined long-term value and cost-effectiveness of change requests

Skills used: JavaScript, CSS, HTML, jQuery, customer relations, working remote

#### Community Manager

Santa Monica, CA

Demand Media

December 2011-July 2014

- Chiefly responsible for RSS Graffiti, a SaaS for automatically publishing content to Facebook and Twitter which powered over 250 million impression daily
- Handled customer support and social media marketing
- Analyzed web traffic data and specified algorithm improvements to be implemented by engineering team
- RSS Graffiti was sold to ScribbleLive in July 2014

Skills used: Python, RSS, JIRA, RabbitMQ, MongoDB, product management, planning, customer support, UX design, data analysis

#### Education

# University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA)

**Political Science** 

Los Angeles, CA 2006–2010

### **Additional Information**

- Awarded a Google bug bounty in July 2005 and accepted into the Google Vulnerability Reward Program Hall of Fame
- Created <u>Sojourn</u>, a platform for sharing vacation homes with friends and family
- Created <u>Corgi Party</u>, a platform for making simple gif sites, which has seen over 30 million visits and hosts over 1 million user-generated pages
- Created <u>@itsavailable</u>, a Twitter bot that programmatically discovers unregistered .com domains
- Co-created <u>Citi Bike Map</u>, a site for viewing NYC bike share availability
- Created this resume template in HTML and CSS